(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T05:00:44.411056",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな！ORIOです！
Everyone! We're ORIO!
今日が初ライブ、その目にしっかり焼き付けてね！
Today's our first live, so burn it into your eyes!
些細な事 ささくれ立って
Getting prickly over trivial things,
いつの間にか 痛みだしてた
before I knew it, it started hurting.
ひとりじゃないって 分かってるけど
I know I'm not alone, but
どうしても孤独に飲まれそう
I feel like I'll be swallowed by solitude.
同じ場所で躓いても
Even if we stumble in the same place,
少しずつ進んでいければいいから
as long as we can move forward step by step.
触れられなくてもここには
Even if I can't touch it, right here
確かな光あるんだ
there is a certain light.
ボクらは散るまでずっとサバイバー
We are survivors until the very end,
道なき道を往く
walking paths where there are none.
誰もが迷える子羊なんだ
Everyone is a stray lamb.
聞かせて小さなことも
Let me hear even the smallest things.
ah 完璧じゃなくても
Ah, even if it's not perfect,
前を向けたのならきっと繋がっていく
if you look ahead, we will surely connect.
終わりのない闇の中で
In the endless darkness,
俯いてはあふれ出す溜息
hanging my head, sighs overflow.
出口のないことばかりを
Thinking only of things with no exit,
考えたまた繰り返して
repeating it over and over.
うまく伝えられなくても
Even if I can't express it well,
言葉を重ねてみたいんだよ
I want to stack our words together.
踏み出す一歩は怖くても
Even if the first step is frightening,
その先の景色見たいんだ
I want to see the scenery beyond it.
天使と悪魔がついているから
Because an angel and a demon are with you.
いつでもすぐそばに
Always right by your side,
荒波だらけの戦場なんだ
in this battlefield of rough seas.
ボクらはきっと大丈夫
We will surely be alright.
ah 痛みの分だけ
ah, by as much as the pain
強くなれてるんだって信じてる
I believe we're growing stronger.
知らずに「普通」の檻に囚われていた無意識を
The unconscious mind trapped in the cage of "normality"
そっと解放してみてよ さぁ
Gently try to set it free, now...
ボクらは散るまでずっとサバイバー
We are survivors until the very end,
道なき道を行く
walking the pathless path.
誰もが迷える子羊なんだ
Everyone is a lost lamb.
聞かせて小さなことも
Let me hear even the smallest things.
ah 完璧じゃなくても前を向いたのならきっと繋がっていく
ah, even if not perfect, looking forward will surely connect us.
諦めない そう決めたの
I won't give up, I decided that.
朱き心を燃やして 燃やして
Burning my crimson heart, burning it on.
正解か不正解かは
Whether it's right or wrong
どうだっていいんだってさ
doesn't matter at all.
走り抜けた足跡 そのまま
The footprints I ran through, just as they are,
物語になっていく 擦りむいて
turning into a story. Scraping my...
擦りむいた 瘡蓋なぞって
tracing the grazed scabs,
痛みをチカラに変えていくんだ
I'll turn the pain into strength.
何度も翼広げて
Spreading my wings over and over,
ここに刻む鼓動だけが真実のsign
only the heartbeat carved here is the sign of truth.
限界だって 吹き飛ばしてく 燃えて燃えて燃え尽きてても
Blowing away any limits, even if I burn and burn out,
また蘇る 決して諦めたくはないから
I'll revive once more, because I never want to give up.
Like a Phoenix
揺れて躓いても
Even if I sway and stumble,
消えない灯火
the light will not go out
心駆り立てるから 幾度も灰になっても構わない
because it spurs my heart. I don't care if I turn to ashes time and time again.
見上げれば 高すぎる空
If I look up, the sky is too high,
眩暈がしても 止められないんだ
even if I feel dizzy, I can't stop.
感情を滾らせながら
While letting my emotions surge,
光求め もがいている 本能のscream
struggling for the light, the scream of instinct.
停滞なんてぶち壊して 打ち壊してく
Shattering stagnation, smashing it apart.
息を切らし不器用でも辿り着くから
Out of breath and clumsy, I'll still reach it,
最短距離で駆け抜けたいたいんだ Like a Phoenix
I want to dash through the shortest distance. Like a Phoenix
声を枯らしてもまだ
Even if my voice grows hoarse,
届けたい熱が冷めなくて
the heat I want to convey won't cool down.
溢れてく 思いの分だけ 決意を速度に変えて
As much as the overflowing feelings, turning determination into speed.
決意を速度に変えて
Turning my resolve into speed,
higher!
何度も翼広げて
Spreading my wings over and over,
爪先伸ばして
stretching out my toes,
ここに刻む鼓動だけが真実のsign
only the heartbeat carved here is the true sign.
限界だって
Even if it's our limit,
吹き飛ばしてく
we'll blow it away!
燃えて燃えて燃え尽きてもまた甦る
Even if we burn, burn, and burn out, we revive once more.
決して諦めたくはないから
Because we never want to give up—
Like a Phoenix
Pray
[Song: Pray]
Speak up about your unspoken prayer
We are the one that rescues you right now
We are the one that rescues you all
禁じ手だらけの人生
A life full of forbidden moves,
演じてるような理想郷
a utopia as if we're acting it out.
今日だけは全て解き放って
Just for today, let it all go and set it free—
信じてみるのもいいね
it's not bad to try believing.
決して忘れることのない
Something we will never forget...
音を聞かせるから
because I'll make you hear the sound!
Just wake up here we are to save you
だから Just wake up here we are to save you
So just wake up here we are to save you
行こうか Just wake up here we are to save you
Shall we go? Just wake up here we are to save you
その手伸ばし祈れ
Stretch out your hand and pray!
Pray Pray Pray
疑うなら Show me what you got then
If you doubt, show me what you got then,
倦うなら I'm so tired
if you're jaded, I'm so tired.
従うなら I'm gonna give you chances
If you obey, I'm gonna give you chances.
Let me take you to the hell もしくは to the heaven
Let me take you to the hell, or to the heaven!
歌えるなら Make a sound right here
If you can sing, make a sound right here—
他には何もいらない そうでしょ？
we don't need anything else, right?
Speak up about your unspoken prayer
We are the one that rescues you right now
Speak up about your unspoken prayer We are the one that rescues you right now
Here we are (Speak up about your unspoken prayer We are the one that rescues you all)
疑うなら Just wake up here we are to save you
If you doubt, just wake up here we are to save you
行こうか Just wake up here we are to save you
Shall we go? Just wake up here we are to save you
その手伸ばし祈れ
Stretch out your hand and pray!
Pray Pray Pray
禁じ手だらけの人生
A life full of forbidden moves,
演じてたはずの理想郷
a utopia we should have been acting out.
今日からは全てぶち壊してみて
From today, smash it all to pieces—
信じているならいっそ
if you believe, might as well go all out.
決して忘れることのない
Something we will never forget...
音を鳴らしてよ
because I'll make the sound ring out!
疑うなら Show me what you got then
If you doubt, show me what you got then,
倦うなら I'm so tired
if you're jaded, I'm so tired.
従うなら I'm gonna give you chances
If you obey, I'm gonna give you chances.
Let me take you to the hell もしくは to the heaven
Let me take you to the hell, or to the heaven!
歌えるなら Make a sound right here
If you can sing, make a sound right here—
他には何もいらない そうでしょ？
we don't need anything else, right?
歌え 騒え 宴は続く
Sing, make some noise, the banquet goes on!
舞え おにけもだんす
Dance to the Oni-Kemo Dance!
や や や
Ya, ya, ya
おにきつねいる じんじゃ！
Demon, fox, dog shrine!
一二三で七変化
Transforming seven ways in one, two, three.
今宵も集え 電気通信網（インターネット）
Gather tonight on the internet.
推し事に幸あれ 此処はまるで桃源郷
Blessings to our devotion; this place is like a utopia.
いっせーので よいよいよい
On three, yoi yoi yoi!
浮世に隠れツノ光る
Hiding in the floating world, horns shining.
どっちでも よいよいよい 我が道を行け
Either way, yoi yoi yoi, walk your own path.
ゆらゆらり 恋焦がれ
Swaying, pining with love.
刹那に燃ゆる この想いは
This burning feeling in the moment...
まだ分からないけど
...is still unknown, but
実らせて 咲き乱れよ
let it bear fruit and bloom wildly.
御人も獣も通りゃんせ 狐犬狸も飛び回れ
Humans and beasts alike, pass on; foxes, dogs, and raccoons, fly around.
命は短し 我武者らに刻め
Life is short; carve it recklessly.
一富士二鷹で百は鬼
First Fuji, second hawk, a hundred demons.
千客万来 おいでませ
Welcome, all visitors,
天晴れお祭りじゃ 打ちまくれ
what a splendid festival; beat the drums!
歌え騒げ 宴は続く 舞え おにけもだんす
Sing and make merry, the feast continues; dance the Onikemo Dance.
余っ余っ余っ余っ
Yotta yotta yotta yotta...
コンコンコンコン
Kon kon kon kon...
にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん
Nyan nyan nyan nyan...
さぁさぁ お手を拝借！
Now then, lend me your hands!
鬼火飛ばして 悪戯したい
Flying demon fires, wanting to play mischief
人間様と駄酒落遊び（あら余っと！）
in idle drinking games with humans (ara yotto!)
親に薬と中指付けて
Applying medicine and middle fingers to parents,
好ごとは激辛稲荷寿司（コンッ）
our favorite is super spicy Inari sushi (kon!)
犬も歩けば占い当たる
Even a dog walking finds fortune,
出でよ召喚ハトタウルーズ（うわぁっビックリしたぁ！）
appear, summoned Hatotaurus (whoa, that startled me!)
超課金書鴉（スーパーチャット）もう よいよいよい
Super Chats too, yoi yoi yoi!
小判を投げて圧かける
Throwing Koban coins to pressure them.
めんこい阿呆 てぇてぇな 甘き夢見し
Cute fools, precious ones, dreaming sweet dreams.
ふわふわり 優しい風
Fluffy, gentle wind,
華麗に花が散れるように
like flowers falling gracefully.
少し切ないけど
It's a little bittersweet, but
見届けて 咲き誇るわ
watch over us as we bloom proudly.
物怪（もののけ）偶像（アイドル）神仏 仮想（バーチャル）現世（リアル）も垣根無し
Monsters, idols, deities; virtual and real have no boundaries.
尻尾を振り回し 天下掴もうぜ
Wagging our tails, let's seize the world.
心象風景 生放送
Mental landscapes, live broadcast.
欄は無くとも奇策は有り 魂を込めて
No rail yet clever tricks remain; put your soul into it,
打ちまくれ
and beat the drums!
歌え騒げ 宴は続く 舞え おにけもだんす
Sing and make merry, the feast continues; dance the Onikemo Dance.
言いたいことがあるんだ余！
There's something I want to say, yo!
やっぱりケモミミ可愛いよ！
Beast ears are the cutest after all!
好ごこ大好ごこやっぱ好こ！
Love 'em, super love 'em, love 'em most!
やっと見つけたお嬢さま！
I finally found you, my lady!
過去と未来を繋いでく！
Connecting the past and the future!
夢を追いかけどこまでも！
Chasing our dreams to the ends of the earth!
世界で一番、愛してる！ ア・イ・シ・テ・ル！
I love you more than anyone in the world! I l-o-v-e y-o-u!
しゃなしゃなり 凸いでく
Shuttling along, charging ahead.
狐の嫁入り の後には
After the fox's wedding,
虹が出ているから
a rainbow is coming out,
紡がせて
so let us weave it on.
咲き続けましょう 踊りましょう
Let's keep blooming, let's keep dancing.
御人も獣も通りゃんせ 狐犬狸も飛び回れ
Humans and beasts alike, pass on; foxes, dogs, and raccoons, fly around.
命は短し 我武者らに刻め
Life is short; carve it recklessly.
一富士二鷹で百は鬼
First Fuji, second hawk, a hundred demons.
千客万来 おいでませ 天晴れお祭りじゃ 打ちまくれ
Welcome, all visitors; what a splendid festival, beat the drums!
歌え騒げ 宴は続く 舞え おにけもだんす
Sing and make merry, the feast continues; dance the Onikemo Dance.
余っ余っ余っ余っ
Yotta yotta yotta yotta...
コンコンコンコン
Kon kon kon kon...
にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん
Nyan nyan nyan nyan...
鬼・狐・犬・神社～！
Demon, fox, dog shrine!
わぁー！
Woo!
いやぁ最初からちょっと激しい曲やっちゃいましたね
Man, we started right off with quite an intense song!
やっちゃいましたね
We sure did.
やっておりますけれども
We're doing it, though!
いやあ皆さん見てくれてありがとうございます！
Man, thank you everyone for watching!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ってことで改めてね自己紹介をしていきましょう！
So with that, let's do our self-introductions properly!
いろはにほへと あやふみ ふぶと と なのかな？白上フブキです！
Iroha ni hoheto, Ayahumi... Fubutton and what was it? Shirakami Fubuki!
いろはにほへと　あやふみ？
Iroha ni hoheto, Ayafumi?
ふぶたっとだよ！
It's Fubutatto!
えーと綾芽踏みの… あやタントのなきりあやめでーす！
Um, Ayayume's... Ayatanto's Nakiri Ayame here!
お待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
あ、や、ほほみ…の
Ah, ya, Hohomi... no
み、担当の…
Mi, in charge of Mi...
おおかみお…おおかみお…びお、です！
Ookami O... Ookami O... Mio, desu!
あれ、どこへやってしまったのか…
Huh, where did I put it...
いなくなった、いなくなりました。どこいっちゃった？
It's gone, it disappeared. Where did it go?
ってことでね、1曲目はね、皆さん大好き鬼ケモダンス
So anyway, for the first song, everyone's favorite Onikemo Dance
踊らせていただきましたけども…いやあ、疲れたね。
we got to dance, but... man, I'm tired.
疲れたね。
I'm tired.
いや、しんどいです。
Yeah, it's tough.
いや、やほほみの中でこれがマックスだから。これがマックス。
Well, within Yahohomi, this is max. This is max.
そうそうそうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
いや、この後も曲が控えてるということでね。
Well, we have more songs lined up after this, so...
ちょっとお前たち恐ろしいこと、恐ろしいこと言ってるけども、はい。
Wait, you guys are saying some terrifying things, yeah.
ちなみにさっきの鬼ケモ間違えた人ー！
By the way, who messed up Onikemo earlier?!
はーい！はーい！
Mee! Mee!
細かいところちょこちょこ間違えてると思うんですけどもね。
I think we messed up the little details here and there, though.
いや、ね、足とかこれね、ぐちゃぐちゃだったもんね。
Yeah, I mean, our feet and stuff were all messy.
まあね、でも、ちゃ、カメラで見えてない
Well, but, maybe it wasn't seen on camera,
可能生もあるかもしれないのでね、まあそれをちょっと…
so... let's just hope that...
見えてないかもしれないので、お祈りというか…
since it might not be visible, let's pray or...
見ないふりしてください。みんなで見ないふりをね、お願いしまーす！
please pretend you didn't see it. Everyone, please pretend you didn't see it!
ね。でも、しかしこうやってね、なんか鬼ケモもね、
Right? But even so, like this, Onikemo too,
なんか、ホロライブの公式放送で踊ったっけ？
did we dance it on Hololive's official broadcast?
踊ったことない…ないよね？踊ったことはない。ないよね、初めてじゃない？
We've never danced it... right? We've never danced it. Never, right? It's our first time, right?
初お披露目みたいな。
Like a first reveal.
初お披露目みたいなのね。まあ、MVではね踊ってましたけどね。
Like a first reveal. Well, we danced in the MV, though.
MVではね、踊ってましたけどもね、みんなさ、これTikTokとかにも上がっててね、
We danced in the MV, but everyone, you know, this is up on TikTok and stuff,
色んな方がね、踊って下さいますけど、みなさんちゃんと踊ってくれましたこれ？
and various people have danced it, but did you guys actually dance this?
トゥトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥ…
Tututututu...
カラオケとかで踊ってこうよとかね。ねえ、みなさんちゃんと言ってくれましたか？
Let's dance it at karaoke or something. Hey, did you guys properly do it?
いや、でもね、皆さん踊ってくれましたかね？踊ってくれた？
Well, but did everyone dance it? Did you dance it?
いや、やっぱりケモミミかわいいよー！
Man, after all, kemomimi are so cute!
スカッとする、スカッとした、跳んでね。
It feels refreshing, refreshing, jumping around.
よよよよよ…ランプみたいになってますけども。
Yoyoyoyo... it's becoming like a lamp.
そうだなあ。でもこの曲、やっぱり1曲目あっていいよね。ねえ、楽しいね。
That's right. But this song is great as a first song. Right, it's fun.
楽しかった、楽しかった。またね、鬼ケモダンスみたいな曲もね、3人で踊れたらいいなー！
It was fun, it was fun. Also, I hope the three of us can dance a song like Onikemo Dance again!
チラッチラッ。
Glance, glance.
チラッチラッ。あ、もうちょっと速さ的にはもうちょっと落としてもいい？
Glance, glance. Ah, should we drop the speed a bit more?
いやね、もうちょっとゆっくりでも。もっと早くなってくるかもしれない、今度は。
Well, even a bit slower. It might get even faster next time.
え、もっとさらに上がっていく？さらにもしかすると、さらに上を行く？
Eh, going even higher? Even more, maybe going even further above?
限界出場よ、限界の。
Reaching the limit appearance, of the limit.
だから、ダンスやるやつってもしかすと、ちょっと、ケレしながらやる。
So, doing the dance might be done while panting a little.
それはまずい、それはまずい。
That's bad, that's bad.
あともっとBPも落とした感じの曲とかね、歌ったらね、ゆったりでおねがいします。
And also songs with lower BPM, if we sing them, please make it relaxing.
適度にね、適度にね。そう、適度にね。はい。
Moderately, moderately. Yes, moderately. Yes.
そしてそして、次の曲は？お、何を歌うんですか？
And then, what's the next song? Oh, what are you going to sing?
お、何を歌うんですか？Mioさん。
Oh, what are you going to sing, Mio-san?
次の曲いっちゃいますか？いいですか？いっちゃいますか？
Shall we go to the next song? Is that okay? Shall we go?
まあ、実はね、我々発表させていただいた曲で、まだダンスをお披露目してない曲ありますよね。
Well, actually, among the songs we announced, there's one where we haven't revealed the dance yet, right?
あ！
Ah!
そうです、そういえば！曲はみんな聴いたことあるけどダンスはね、聞いたことないと思うんですけども。
That's right, now that you mention it! Everyone's heard the song, but I think you haven't seen the dance.
そうだよね。その曲をやっちゃおうかなって。
That's right. So we might just do that song.
え？やっちゃいますか？そんなに動いて大丈夫ですか？この後のダンスは。
Eh? Shall we do it? Will we be okay moving that much for the next dance?
いや、やばいよ。やばいやばいやばい。もうやっちゃったね。準備していきましょうかね。
Man, it's dangerous. Dangerous dangerous. Well, we've done it. Let's get ready.
準備していきましょうか。はいはいはいはい。
Let's get ready. Yes yes yes yes.
準備しちゃおかしら。行きますか。この状態で後ろ向いては聞いてくださいって。
Shall we get ready? Here we go. Turn around in this state and listen, she says.
こっち向いてっちゅうの！それでは聞いてください！
Face this way! Now, please listen!
宵闇見倚り！
Yoiyami Miiri!
鬼灯日和
[Song: Hoozuki Biyori]
沈む茜日 染まる坂道
Setting madder sun, a dyed slope
つたう雫に 嬉しさ滲む
Joy seeps into the trickling droplets
夜の帳の 近付く音に
To the approaching sound of night's curtain
はしゃいだキモの声ひとつ 空に響いた
A playful kimo's voice echoed into the sky
稲荷の前で 待ち合わせ
Meeting up in front of the Inari shrine
連なる鳥居くぐり抜け
Passing through the line of torii gates
鬼灯の甘い風 胸をすり抜けていく
The sweet wind of hoozuki slips right through my chest
「踊ろうよ」
"Let's dance"
廻れ 廻れ 手を叩いて ほら
Spin, spin, clapping your hands, look
見様見真似で 輪になって
Making a circle by imitation
ぎこちない 振り付けに舞う
Dancing to clumsy choreography
袖はひらひら
Sleeves fluttering
踊れ 踊れ 手を取り合って
Dance, dance, holding hands together
上気した頬 牡丹色
Cheeks flushed peony-colored
鳴り響く 太鼓の音に
To the resounding sound of drums
紅い果実弾けた
A red fruit burst open
A crimson fruit bursts open,
キミに気付けたかな？
Did you notice me?
響くざわめき 燃ゆる篝火
Echoing murmurs and burning bonfires,
揺らぐ気持ちに想い乗せよう
Let's put our feelings into these wavering hearts.
祭り囃子が遠く音に
As festival music plays in the distance,
天狼の星の雲隠れ 胸を突いた
The Wolf star hides behind the clouds, piercing my chest.
今宵 空には朧月 霞んだ心誤魔化した
Tonight, a hazy moon fills the sky, masking my clouded heart.
玉響に揺らいで胸をすり抜けたら
Wavering momentarily, slipping through my chest,
目を閉じて 眠れ眠れ 意識は透明
Close your eyes, sleep and slumber, consciousness transparent.
一夜一夜に募る想い 月明かり照らす花びら 散るはらはら
Feelings grow night after night as moonlight illuminates falling petals.
哭いて哭いて流るる雫 嫁入り前の小夜時雨
Crying and weeping tears, a night shower before marriage.
傘の外 狐日和 神隠し櫛だ キミに気付かれないように
Outside the umbrella, fox weather, a spirited-away comb, so you won't notice.
天つ風 雲の通り路
Heavenly winds, the path of the clouds,
閉ざし見ゆる夢のまにまに
Lost within the closed dreamscape.
幾星霜 想い焦がれた
Yearned for over countless ages,
このひと時が絶えませぬように
May this moment never fade away,
ぽつり願う
I quietly wish.
止まれ 止まれ 時間よ止まれ 夢の心地をご笑味あれ
Stop, stop, time stop, savor the feeling of a dream.
狐火の狼煙に乗せた 心ゆらゆら
Riding the beacon fire of fox-fires, hearts swaying to and fro.
踊れ 踊れ 手を取り合って 軽快な歩調 水鏡
Dance, dance, holding hands, light-footed steps on a water mirror.
幸への百鬼夜行に 連なる思い出たち 今宵 キミに幸あれ
Memories linked in a Night Parade of One Hundred Demons leading to happiness, tonight happiness to you.
どわー！
Whoa!
やりきりましたね！
We made it through!
どうでしたか皆さん？
How was it, everyone?
いやあねえ、初初ド緊張披露目でしたね
Man, this was our very first debut performance, so we were super nervous!
なんか踊り忘れちゃって
I kind of forgot the choreography...
忘れちゃったよね！でも楽しかったねこの曲ね、ダンス
We totally forgot! But dancing to this song was so much fun!
で、なんですけども、なんと、なんと！
And that's not all—guess what, guess what!
もう一曲...あ、え？今日はあるんですよね？
There's another song... Oh, wait? We have one today, right?
そうですね、もう一曲...ある...あるんですよね？
That's right, another song... Right, we have one?
はい！それは何かと言いますと...え？一丁っすか？
Yes! And what could that be? ...Eh? Just one?
え、え？やったほうがいいですか？えー！一丁、一丁なんですか？
Eh, eh? Should we do it? What, just one? Really?
我々の残されてる曲、まあもう1曲ありますもんね
We still have another song left, after all.
まあありますけど、百鬼夜行の、あの雰囲気、ではないで...ではないですか？ねえ！
We do, but isn't that totally different from the Hyakki Yakou vibe? Right?!
え、ちょっと！あと、このあと24時から配信が開始されます！
Wait a minute! Also, starting at midnight tonight, the stream begins!
我々いろはにほへと アヤハミ 新曲「連鎖シコウ」！
Our new song by Iroha ni Hoheto Ayahami, 'Rensa Shikou'!
えー！連鎖シコウ...あ、連鎖シコウ...そんな曲じゃなくて...どんな曲なのかな？
Eh?! 'Rensa Shikou'... Wait, that's not the kind of song... What kind of song is it?
今回初お披露目ということで、ちょっとね、今までのと違ったね、楽曲と
Since this is our first performance of it, it's a bit different from our previous songs...
って、お、なっておりますよね？
So it's finally time, right?
どんな曲なのかなー？
I wonder what kind of song it is?
どんな曲なんでしょうかね？
What kind of song could it be?
ひとりやだーい！
I don't want to be alone!
ひとりやだーい！このあとやるんだぞ！
I don't want to be alone! We're doing it after this!
かわいい感じかな？
A cute kind of vibe?
あ、たしかに。ねえ。
Ah, true. Right.
和風な感じ？和風ね！かわいい感じなの、どうなのかなー？
A Japanese style? Japanese style! A cute vibe, I wonder how it is?
どうなのかなー？
I wonder how it is?
やりますかじゃ。
Shall we do it then?
聞いてみてからのお楽しみ！ お楽しみに！ことほ！
It's a surprise after you listen! Look forward to it!
ではではでは、最初、位置覚えてますか？
Now then, do you remember your starting positions?
どうだったっけね？
How was it again?
やばいやばい！やばい！どうだったっけね？
Oh no! Oh no! How was it again?
あーこんな感じだったかな？どうです？ここですよ、ここですよもう。
Ah, was it like this? How is it? It's right here, right here!
まず忘れないから、歌詞も大丈夫かい？覚えてるかい、ちゃんと？ええと、ええと。
First, don't forget. Are the lyrics okay too? Do you remember them properly? Um...
ええと、連省しかっていうのはもう、なんかもう二人ともちょっと不安になってきましたな。まあでも行きましょうかね、じゃあね。
Um, "Renjou Shika"... the two of us are getting a bit nervous. Well, but shall we go, then?
じゃみんなで行きますよタイトル。それでは聴いてください。せーの。
Then everyone, we're going with the title. Please listen. Ready, set.
連省しかー！
Renjou Shika!
言えぬ言葉の数を数えてみては
Counting up all the unspoken words,
（一二、一二三四、五六七八と）
(One, two, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight,)
小さなこの両手じゃ数えきれない
My two small hands can't hold them all,
愛の唄が今も生まれ
and a love song is born once again.
頭隠していても
Even if you hide your head,
角も尻尾も隠せない止められない
you can't hide your horns or tail, you can't stop it!
覗いては雲隠れ 乙女の恋情詩歌
Peeking through clouds, a maiden's passionate ode.
気付かずに気がついてよ
Without realizing, please notice me—
秘め事は五月の闇
my secret is the darkness of May.
その向こうで舞い踊る
Dancing beyond that barrier,
恋、慕う君へと伝うように
so this love reaches the one I yearn for.
みんな盛り上がってる？最後までちゃんとついてきてくれるんだよ！いくぞー！
Are you all hyped up? Make sure you keep up till the end! Let's go!
側で聞こえてしまう程鳴り響く
Echoing so close you can hear it,
（ドキドッキンドキッ！ドキドッキンドキッ！）
(Thump-thump-thump, thump-thump-thump!)
心塞いでも増すばかりで
even when I lock my heart away, it only grows,
クラクラする程の感情
a dizzying surge of emotion.
目線逸らしてみても
Even if I look away,
角も尻尾も隠せない止められない
you can't hide your horns or tail, you can't stop it!
夢見ては雲越えて 乙女の恋情詩歌
Dreaming beyond the clouds, a maiden's passionate ode.
愛さずに愛していてよ
While pretending not to, please love me—
裏腹心は五月の闇
my contradictory heart is the darkness of May.
その向こうに何を見る
What do you see on the other side?
愛、慕う君へと届くように
So this love reaches the one I adore,
真心の鬼火そっと灯す アイラブユウの数光らせば
softly lighting a sincere will-o'-the-wisp. Let Mio's "I love you" shine bright!
化かしてあげましょうほら夢中 捧げるものなら辛口で
Let me bewitch you, look, get lost in a dream. If you want an offering, make it spicy!
高く声あげりゃさあ集まれ どこに居たって遠く響かせ
Raise your voices high, come gather round. Wherever you are, let it echo far!
物の怪乙女の三人衆 そこらのけそこらのけ我等が通る
A trio of supernatural maidens—move aside, make way as we pass through!
恋しと、君へと届くように
So that my love can reach you...
はじまーる！はじまーる！はじまーる！
Here it begins, begins, begins!
宿題が全っっ然終わらない、全国のヤバめな諸君！
Homework isn't finished at all, you troubled souls nationwide!
時間がなければ、眠らなきゃいいじゃない
If you don't have time, just don't sleep!
がんばれ、がんばれ、あたし…
Do your best, do your best, me...
パーリラ脳内フロア
Party-loving brain floor
暴れてるカルナバル
A rampaging carnival
アドレナリン ドバドバ
Adrenaline pumping endlessly
究極のPANIGHT
The ultimate PANIGHT
パリナイ！パリナイ！パーラパッパパリナイ！
Pirinai! Pirinai! Pa-ra-pa-ppa pirinai!
We Are ＼NEGI☆U／ Let's go !
スゴイ ヤバイ パない 物足りない
Amazing, dangerous, unreal, not enough!
ないない尽くしてとどめない(とどめない)
Endless, unyielding desires (unyielding)
スゴイ ヤバイ パない Saturday Night
Amazing, dangerous, unreal, Saturday Night!
とにかくもう やるしかない(やるしかない)
Anyway, we just have to do it (have to do it)
どすこい(どすこい！) ヤバイ パない 物足りない
Dosukoi! Dangerous, unreal, not enough!
全カモノモノ申したい(申したい)
I want to fully voice all my complaints (voice them)
たった一度の青春は(わー!?)
A once-in-a-lifetime youth (What!?)
毎日ENJOY！Party Night(ぱーりなーい!)
Everyday ENJOY! Party Night (Party Night!)
あーお集りの旦那様、えー、そうじゃない様、ご唱和ください
Ah, assembled gentlemen, er, or not gentlemen, please chant along!
それゆけSay Now Wow...
Here we go, Say Now Wow...
ddddj!!
PA PA PA PA... PANIGHT!!
うえーーーーーーん
Waaaaah~~~~n
Everybody Sing Along(Sing Along)
Everybody Sing Along (Sing Along)
でっち上げ進化論(進化論)
Fabricated theory of evolution (Evolution)
陽キャでも陰キャでも勉強だWassup!!(Wassup!!)
Extrovert or introvert, it's study time, Wassup!! (Wassup!!)
太陽は銀河系？(銀河系？)
Is the sun part of the galaxy? (Galaxy?)
おしゃべりノンノンノン！(ノンノンノン！)
Chatterbox non-no-no! (No-no-no!)
遊んじゃダメダメ(ダメダメ)
Don't play around, no-no (No-no)
ごめんなさーい！(ごめんなさーい！)
We're so sorry! (So sorry!)
朝が来て眠れない どうしよう…
Morning comes and I can't sleep, what should I do...
神様も両手挙げてFly High
Even God raises both hands, Fly High
なんとかするしかない 頑張れ出来るって
We somehow have to do it, do your best, you can do it
ド派手にかましちゃう ネバギバ Put your hands up
Making a flashy entrance, Never give up, Put your hands up
タリナイ！タリナイ！ターラタッタ タリナイ！
Not enough! Not enough! Ta-ra-ta-tta not enough!
タリナイ！タリナイ！時間がない(時間がない)
Not enough! Not enough! There's no time (No time)
We Are ＼NEGI☆U／ Let's go !
あ、えと、れっつごー！w
Ah, erm, let's go! lol
スゴイ ヤバイ パない 物足りない 時代のバッター かたじけない
Amazing, dangerous, unreal, not enough! The pinch hitter of the era, much obliged
スゴイ ヤバイ パない Sunday Night とにかくもう やるしかない
Amazing, dangerous, unreal, Sunday Night! Anyway, we just have to do it
どすこい ヤバイ パない 物足りない 宿題やっぱり終わらない
Dosukoi! Dangerous, unreal, not enough! Homework still isn't finished
たった一度の青春は 脳内HAPPY！Party Night
A once-in-a-lifetime youth, Brain HAPPY! Party Night
ねえねえ、あてぃし～、おわんねーよこれー！
Hey hey, Atti, this isn't finishing at all!
スバル先セーイ～！この問題全然わかんないんですけど～！
Subaru-sensei~! I don't understand this problem at all!
えーっ！何その鉛筆！めっちゃ可愛いじゃん、いいなー！
Eh!? What's that pencil! It's so cute, lucky you!
でしょーww キラキラ光るんですよ～ホホホ
Right?ww It sparkles, y'know~ hohoho
えへへ、みんな、げんきだな… よ、陽キャって、こんな時も、すごいなー…
Hehe, everyone's so energetic... Man, extroverts are amazing even at times like this...
はははは……えと……はは……はーりー！w
Hahahaha... um... haha... hurry! lol
やったー！
Yay!
きょうは、みにきてくれて、ありがとー！
Thank you so much for coming to see us today!
えがたでちまーす！ソロライブに来せいおらのすばるー！そして
I'm Egata-de-chimasu! Coming to solo live, our Subaru! And
みなさんどうもこんかぷみなとかぷでーす！そして
Hello everyone, it's Conkap Minato Kap-de-su! And...
こんね～、ももしずねねでーす！よろしくね～！
Konne~ Momosuzu Nene-de-su! Nice to meet you!
わたしたち せーのっ ネギュー！でーす！
We are, ready, NEGI☆U-de-su!
あっ、でもね、すごかったし、最後の赤のパ、パーティ、みたいな
Wait, it was amazing! The ending red pa-, party, like-
パーティイー!
Party!
いや、乗り切れないよね。
I mean, you can't really keep up, right?
え、乗り切れないの?
Eh? You couldn't keep up?
みんなもどちらかっていうとパーティのタイプだよね?
Most of you are more of the "party" type, right?
ねえねえ、熱々、熱々の根本に聞いてみてよ。
Hey hey, let's ask Nene, who's all fired up.
みんなどうだった?あっち先輩もばっちりだった?
How was it for everyone? Did A-chan-senpai nail it too?
うんうん、あっちばっちり。
Yeah yeah, Nene nailed it.
あ、だ、大丈夫だった?
Ah, w-were you okay?
あ、だ、大丈夫、大丈夫だったらしいよ。
Ah, d-, it's okay, apparently she was okay.
本当?良かった。
Really? That's great.
めっちゃ不安だった。
I was super nervous.
すごいかった。良かった。
It was amazing. I'm glad.
でもね、熱々とねスバルはね、もうノリノリでしたかね。
But you know, Nene and Subaru, you were really getting into it.
ねえ、すごかった!
Yeah, it was amazing!
すごい楽しい曲だよね。
It's such a fun song, right?
なんか、ファッションを、両方からのファッションを感じたよ。
Like, you could feel the fashion from both sides!
すごい!
Amazing!
感じだ。じゃあちょっと最後にあのパーティいただいていいですか、渾身の。
I see. Well, could we get one final party, your absolute best?
え、じゃあパーティって言ってから、パーティークって。
Eh, then say "party", and then partyー.
せーの、
Ready, set-
パーティイー!
Party!
やる気出せ!
Show some enthusiasm!
いやでもね、すごい楽しい曲でした!
I mean, it was such a fun song!
ねえ!それは楽しかったよ!
Yeah! It really was fun!
大丈夫、言わされてないよ。台本、台本に書いてあった。
It's fine, I'm not forced to say this. It was in the script!
台本、台本に書いてあった。
Script, it was in the script!
あ、本当だ。
Ah, true.
台本とか!
Script and stuff!
ま、ぜひね、みなさん楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです!
Well, we hope you all enjoyed it!
はーい!
Yes!
え、そしてこの後も、あーげあーげな曲を歌っていきたいと思いますので、
And, we'll continue singing hype songs after this, so
よかったら最後まで楽しんでいってね。
if you'd like, please enjoy it until the end.
じゃあみんな、次の曲の場所に移動だ!
Alright everyone, let's move to the next song location!
あーげ!
Hype!
え、それでは、聞いてください。「ドヤっとVピース☆」
Well then, please listen to "Doyatto V Peace☆"
キメ顔ポーズハイチーズ
Strike a smug pose and say cheese!
ホラV V V V V スマイルで
Hollah V V V V V with a smile!
ドヤっとラッキーラッキー ドレミファニーファニー
Smug and lucky lucky, do-re-mi funny funny,
朝はモリモリ 褒めたくリズミィ
morning is lively, praising rhythmically,
それはハッピーイエーイ
that's happy yay!
寝ぼけ頭に聞こえる おいで おいで の声
In my sleepy head, I hear a voice calling "come on"
片手サイズの世界へ さあ行くぞ 準備バッチオーケー！
To a palm-sized world, let's go, prep is all OK!
かなり！ノリノリ！Onlyでワビサビ感じて 焦がしたバターでタピタピ ラーメンスープ
Quite! Pumped up! Feeling wabi-sabi, ramen soup with butter & tapioca
もーっともーっと楽しもう 夢の中でもお代わりだ
Let's enjoy it more and more, even in dreams it's seconds!
キソウテンガイなおまじない
An eccentric spell
限界が止まらない 今日も（ハッピーを見つけてポッチとな）
Boundaries won't stop, today too (finding happiness and clicking)
明日も（終わらない宿題ポッとな） 全力全開爆発だもん
Tomorrow too (never-ending homework pop) It's a full-throttle explosion!
なんてたってV！ だいじょうV！
No matter what, V! It's alright V!
ドヤっとゆわせちゃうブイブイ！ 最強V！勝利のV！
Making you say it smugly, V-V! Strongest V! Victory V!
チャンネルはそのままで
Keep the channel as it is
なんてたってV！ デリシャスV！
No matter what, V! Delicious V!
アイスクリーム食べて / うんまうま
Eating ice cream / yummy yum
キメ顔ポーズハイチーズ ホラV V V V V スマイルで
Strike a smug pose and say cheese! Hollah V V V V V with a smile!
ドヤ顔キメて！（イイね！イイね！）
Strike a smug face! (Nice! Nice!)
びえんな顔して（イイね！イイね！）
Make a crying face! (Nice! Nice!)
驚いて！（わっ！） ぷんすかぷん！（ぷんっ）
Be surprised! (Wah!) Pouty-pout! (Pout!)
最後にスマイル（わ～～～！）
Finally a smile (wah~~~!)
なんか疲れちゃって ほんわかしたい
Feeling kind of tired, I want to feel warm and fuzzy
そんな時はそうだね 温泉だ！
At times like that, right, hot springs!
パーっとダーっとはしゃいで 旅館でまったりだいらげよう
Let's dash and play, relaxing and feasting at a ryokan
クタクタ茹でたお蕎麦みたい
Like exhausted boiled buckwheat noodles
ふにゃふにゃしちゃっても
Even if we get all limp and soft
我ら（呼ばれて飛び出てドヤドヤ）
We are (summoned and popping out, smugly)
アイドル（あざとくメイクもしちゃおうか） やる時はやる アルデンテ
Idol (let's do sly makeup too) When it's time to do it, we're al dente
だってだってV！ ヴィーナスのV！
No matter what, V! Venus's V!
キラッとカマしちゃえブイブイ！ 最強V！スペアリV！
Dazzlingly pull it off, V-V! Strongest V! Super VIP V!
とにかく腹ペコ そりゃまたV！
Anyway, starving, that's V again!
これまたV！ タイムスリップしたらクラクラ
This is V again! Time slipping makes me dizzy
何処でもポーズハイチーズ ホラV V V V V 輝いて
Strike a pose anywhere, say cheese! Hollah V V V V V shining bright
みんな一緒に手をつないで Vをつくって 行くよ！せーの！
Everyone holding hands together, let's make a V and go! Ready, set!
魅力がハジけちゃう 世界がマネしちゃう
Charm bursts out, the world copies it
いつか（笑った顔が見たいから） 銀河を（ずっと此処で会いたいから）
Someday (because I want to see your smiling face) The galaxy (because I want to meet you right here always))
まとめて罠にしちゃうよ（ビッグバーン！）
I'll trap it all together (Big Bang!)
なんてたってV！ だいじょうV！
No matter what, V! It's alright V!
ドヤっとゆわせちゃうブイブイ！ 最強V！勝利のV！
Making you say it smugly, V-V! Strongest V! Victory V!
チャンネルはそのままで
Keep the channel as it is
なんてたってV！ デリシャスV！
No matter what, V! Delicious V!
アイスクリーム食べて / うんまうま
Eating ice cream / yummy yum
キメ顔ポーズハイチーズ ホラV V V V V
Strike a smug pose and say cheese! Hollah V V V V V
ホラV V V V V スマイルで ドヤっとラッキーラッキー ドレミファニーファニー
Hollah V V V V V with a smile! Smug and lucky lucky, do-re-mi funny funny
ホッペタぷにぷに
Cheeks "Puni Puni" (Puni Puni)
ドヤッとラッキーラッキー
Smug "Lucky Lucky" (Lucky lucky)
ドレミファニファニ
Do-Re-Mi "Funny Funny"
それはハッピーイェーイ！
That's Happy Yeahhhhhh!!!
さあ、ネギU最後の曲です！今日は見に来てくれてありがとうー！
Now, it's NEGI☆U's final song! Thank you so much for coming today!
ありがとうー！ありがとうー！
Thank you! Thank you!
よっしゃ、じゃあ場所移って…えっとどこだっけ？あそこらへんな？
Alright, let's move... Um, where was it? Around there?
はい、それでは聞いてください！欲張りキュートガール！
Yes, then please listen! Yokubari Cute Girl!
ゴーレッツゴー！時間だ 待ち合わせはいつものカフェで
Go! Let's Go! It's time, meeting at our usual cafe
Chu-Chu-Wa Chu-wa-Chu-wa-Chu-Chu
走れ！タントンターン ショートカットで R.A.N.R.U.N. 駆け抜けよう
Run! Tap-ton-turn, taking a shortcut to R.A.N.R.U.N. and dashing through!
Chu-Chu-Wa Chu-wa-Chu-wa-Chu-Chu
たまには 髪型をふわり
Sometimes with a fluffy new hairstyle
おしゃれモードで歩こうよ
Let's walk in fashionable style, come on!
スクランブルで転げちゃって 注目浴びてゴメンって
Tripping at the scramble, sorry for grabbing all the attention!
笑って！(もう！) すぐ怒らないで
Smile! (Jeez!) Don't get mad right away!
楽しい！(楽しい！) 美味しい！(美味しい！) なんでもシェアハピ(ハッピー！)
Fun! (Fun!) Delicious! (Delicious!) Let's share anything & everything (Happy!)
キミと！(キミと！) キミと！(キミと！) 夢みたいな お年頃(お年頃♪)
With you! (With you!) With you! (With you!) At a dreamlike age (Dreamlike age♪)
ワクワクしちゃう ドキドキしちゃう スチャラカモードで(ヨイヨイ！)
Getting excited, getting nervous in our carefree mode (Yoi Yoi!)
よくばりなんです あさってトークパシャリ キュートなエブリデイ
We're greedy girls! Chatting and snapping away every cute day!
出たよね！おニューのアイス
It's out! The brand-new ice cream!
行こうよ！ Hurry! Hurry! (Hurry! Hurry!)
Let's go! Hurry! Hurry! (Hurry! Hurry!)
どれどれ！迷っちゃう
Let's see! I'm so torn!
やっぱいつものパンケーキ(パンケーキ)
As always, the usual pancakes (Pancakes)
見つけた シアワセのカケラ
Found a piece of happiness
ガラスボトル詰め込むの
Stuffed inside a glass bottle
青空テラス キラキラ 楽しみタイの まだまだ
Sparkling blue sky terrace, still want to enjoy much more!
見えるかな？素敵なレインボースカイ
Can you see it? A wonderful rainbow sky!
「さぁ～今日もたくさん買い物するぞ～」
"Now~ let's do lots of shopping today~"
「えへへ、待ってくださいよスバル先輩～」
"Ehehe, wait up, Subaru-senpai~"
「わっ、この服、可愛い…」
"Whoa, this outfit is so cute..."
「お手伝いしますよー！」
"I can help you out!"
「お客さん、お目が高いですね～」
"You have a great eye, customer~"
「さすが先輩、似合うと思いますよ！」
"As expected of our senpai, it suits you!"
「そ、そうかな。えへ、い、いーね！」
"I-Is that so? Hehe, th-that's nice!"
いつも いつも ありがとう
Always, always, thank you
浮かぶ笑顔 シャッターチャンスだぁ！(だぁ！)
Floating smiles, it's a shutter chance! (Chance!)
楽しい！(楽しい！) 美味しい！(美味しい！) なんでもシェアハピ(ハッピー！)
Fun! (Fun!) Delicious! (Delicious!) Let's share anything & everything (Happy!)
キミと！(キミと！) キミと！(キミと！) 夢みたいな お年頃(お年頃♪)
With you! (With you!) With you! (With you!) At a dreamlike age (Dreamlike age♪)
ワクワクしちゃう ドキドキしちゃう スチャラカモードで(ヨイヨイ！)
Getting excited, getting nervous in our carefree mode (Yoi Yoi!)
よくばりなんです
We're greedy girls!
「バナナはお菓子に入りますか～！？」
"Does a banana count as a snack?!"
あれも！(あれも！) これも！(これも！)
That too! (That too!) This too! (This too!)
全部全部欲しいの(ちょーだい！)
We want all of it! (Give it to us!)
作るのだ パラダイス(パラダイス☆)
Creating a paradise (Paradise☆)
おにぎり食べて お菓子も食べて シアワセ笑っちゃう(ヨイイロイ！)
Eating rice balls, eating snacks, smiling in happiness (Yoi Iroi!)
家族みたいだね あさってトークパシャリ キュートなエブリデイ
Just like a family, chatting and snapping away every cute day!
止められない
I can't stop it...
覗いては曇りがくれ、おもむろ連情詩歌
Peeking and turning cloudy, a sudden love elegy
傷つかずに気楽にいてよ
Stay carefree without getting hurt
秘密の底、心からは、毒ガスの闇、その向こうで迷おう
At the bottom of secrets, from the heart, in the darkness of poison gas, let's get lost beyond it
hololive IDOL PROJECT ユニット初集合 Live
[hololive IDOL PROJECT Unit First Gathering Live]